rhymezone.com 2002-06-04

# Lycos Zone Privacy Vow

Lycos, Inc. has created this privacy statement in order to demonstrate our firm commitment to privacy. The following discloses our information gathering and dissemination practices for this Web site: Lycos Zone   
  
---|---  
  
Lycos Zone was designed to provide a safe neighborhood on the Web for children 3 to 12 years old and their families. Lycos Zone is separate from the rest of the Lycos Network, where each site offers distinct features and targets a specific Web audience through unique programming. The policy on this page reflects our company's commitment to the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA) and children's safety on the Internet. To learn more about COPPA within the other properties of the Lycos Network, please visit <http://www.lycos.com/privacy/coppa.html>.

**TRUSTe Certified**  
Lycos Zone is a licensee of the TRUSTe Privacy Program. TRUSTe is an independent, non-profit organization with a mission to build trust and confidence in the Internet by promoting the principles of disclosure and informed consent. Because Lycos Zone wants to demonstrate its commitment to your privacy, we have agreed to disclose our information practices and have our privacy practices reviewed and audited for compliance by TRUSTe. You can verify our TRUSTe license and learn more about their Privacy Program by clicking [here](https://www.truste.org/validate/1031).

**What information is being collected, and who is collecting it?**  
Lycos Zone does not collect any personally identifiable information. We do collect anonymous information in aggregate form as described below in the discussions about cookies and IP addresses. All of the homework, news, fun, parents and teachers zones are available for free, without you having to disclose any information about yourself. 

Lycos Zone also contains links to external Web sites that have been co-branded with Lycos Zone. Registration is not required or requested on most co-branded sites. However, Lycos Zone is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such sites. 

We encourage parents to participate in their child's Internet experience. Children should never give away any information about themselves without getting permission from their parents. 

Some Lycos Zone co-branded sites are operated by educational nonprofit organizations that require some registration information from children with adult consent. Note: the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA) does not apply to nonprofit entities. Registration is required on these sites in order to track the child's success and maintain scores and averages. Parental notification and consent are part of the registration process. Current nonprofit organizations featured on the site are:

**BOOK ADVENTURE** \- If registering at home, a user must provide a first name and first initial of last name. If registering in the classroom, a teacher must register the children. Book Adventure's Privacy Policy states "Unless otherwise disclosed during collection, Book Adventure does not provide any personally identifying information, regardless of its source, to any third party, for any purpose whatsoever." For more information on Book Adventure's privacy policy, click [here](http://www.bookadventure.org/privacy.asp). Contact information for Book Adventure: 1001 Fleet Street, Baltimore, MD 21202, (410) 843-8000, email: [bawebmaster@educate.com](mailto:bawebmaster@educate.com)

**CYBERSURFARI** \- Children registering individually are not allowed to provide any registration information. A notice to parents is immediately sent so that they can register their children, with a follow up confirmation email notice. Teachers need to create teams and then register students. The only required information to enter a student is first name and T-shirt size. For more information on CyberSurfari's privacy policy, click [here](http://www.cybersurfari.org/content.cfm?L1=14&L2=0). Contact information for CyberSurfari: PO Box 748, Annapolis, MD 21404; (410) 647-2111; email: [privacy@cybersurfari.org](mailto:privacy@cybersurfari.org)

The following is a list of additional co-branded sites and the information requested from users: 

**BONUS** \- Children are not required to register unless they wish to track a cumulative score during a session. Those who do wish to track scores are requested to provide a nickname, birth date, email, zip code, and country. Registration requires parents' email to register kids under 13. Parental notification requiring approval within 21 days is included in the registration process. Bonus' Privacy Policy states "Under no circumstances do we rent or sell information about our registered visitors to any outside third party. All personally identifiable information is collected for our own purposes to help us better shape our content to meet the preferences of our audience." For more information on Bonus' privacy policy, click [here](http://www.bonus.com/contour/help/http@@/ww/etc/help/Personalinfo/personalinfo.html). Contact information for Bonus: 824 San Antonio Road, Palo Alto, CA 94303; (650) 813-0100; email: [customer.service@bonus.com](mailto:customer.service@bonus.com)

**GRASSHOPPER** \- During periodic contests, children earn chances to win a PlayStation® 2 computer entertainment systems by answering questions on Safaria's Treasure Hunt quizzes. To enter the contest, all users must provide a valid email address, first name, and date of birth. Children under 13 must include a parent's or legal representative's email address. Email addresses will be used to send a one-time confirmation to all entrants (and parents of children under 13) and a notification to the winner (and parent of winner under 13). Grasshopper's Privacy Policy states "Unless otherwise disclosed during collection, Safaria.com does not provide any personally identifying information, regardless of its source, to any third party for any purpose whatsoever." For more information on Grasshopper's privacy policy, click [here](http://www.safaria.com/privacypol/privacypol.cfm). Contact information for Grasshopper: 10001 NW 50th Street Suite 110; Sunrise, FL 33351; (954) 742-7818; email: [info@safaria.com](mailto:info@safaria.com)

**Does Lycos Zone use cookies?**  
A cookie is a small text file containing a unique identification number that is transferred from a Web site to the hard drive of your computer so that the site administrator may identify your computer and passively track its activities on the Web site. A cookie will not let a Web site know any personally identifiable information about you, such as your real name or address.

Lycos Zone sets a user cookie when a person visits our pages so we can recognize the number of unique users who visit our site. Lycos Zone does not interact with any other cookies that are used by other sites within the Lycos Network or third party sites. Some Lycos Zone co-branded sites will set additional user cookies when you visit their pages, also for the purpose of recognizing unique visitors. 

If you prefer, you can reset your browser to notify you when you have received a cookie. You can also refuse to accept cookies altogether. Lycos Zone does not require you to use cookies.

**What about IP addresses?**  
Lycos Zone collects IP addresses for the purposes of system administration and to report aggregate information to our advertisers. No personally identifiable information is collected along with your IP address. If advertisers ask, Lycos Zone will provide them only with information on which ISP a visitor came from (AOL, MindSpring, etc.) or the type of browser used. However, most advertisers don't care about or ask for such information.

**Notification of Changes**  
Lycos Zone does not collect any personally identifiable information. If we decide to change this policy we will inform users with a statement on our site.

If you have questions or concerns regarding this statement, you should first contact Lycos Zone's Privacy Site Coordinator:

Lycos Zone Privacy Site Coordinator  
Lycos, Inc.  
400-2 Totten Pond Road  
Waltham, MA 02154  
(781) 370-2700  
(781) 370-2600 (Fax)  

If you do not receive acknowledgment of your inquiry or your inquiry has not been satisfactorily addressed, you should then contact TRUSTe at <http://www.truste.org/users/users_watchdog.html>. TRUSTe will then serve as a liaison with Lycos Zone to resolve your concerns.
